[MUSIC]
[موسيقى]
Now we've seen multiple ways that overfitting can be bad for
والآن، نكون قد شاهدنا العديد من الطرق التي يمكن أن يكون التطابق المفرط فيها سيئًا
classification especially from logistic regression and
للتصنيف وخصوصًا من الانحدار اللوجستي،
how very massive parameters can be a really bad thing.
وكيف أن المعلمات الضخمة جدًا، تكون سيئة للغاية،
So, what we're going to do next is introduce a notion of regularization
ولذا، ما سنقوم به بعد ذلك، هو تقديم فكرة التنظيم،
just like we did regression to penalize this really large parameters
كما قمنا بالانحدار للتخلص من تلك المعلمات الكبيرة جدًا،
in order to get a more reasonable outcome.
وذلك من أجل الحصول على قدر أكبر من الدخل المعقول.
So we're still talking about the same logistical regression model
ولذا، فإننا نظل نتحدث عن نفس نموذج الانحدار اللوجستي،
where we take data we do some feature extraction to it we fit
عندما نأخذ البيانات ونقوم ببعضٍ من استخراج الميزات،
this model one over one plus e to the minus w transpose x.
لملاءمة هذا النموذج من خلال 1+e مرفوع لأس -w منقولة مصفوفة x.
But the quality metric for this machine in the algorithm is going to change
ولكن مقياس الجودة لخوارزمية التعلم الآلي سيتغير،
to push us away from really large coefficients.
ليدفعنا بعيدًا عن المعاملات الضخمة.
So in particular we're going to balance how well we fit the data
ولذا، وعلى وجه الخصوص، سنقوم بالموازنة بين بالكيفية التي نقوم من خلالها بملاءمة البيانات
with the magnitude of coefficients as to avoid this massive coefficients.
مع حجم المعاملات من اجل تجنب المعاملات الضخمة.
In the context of logistic regression,
وفي سياق الانحدار اللوجستي،
we're balancing two things to measure total quality.
سنقوم بالموازنة بين شيئين لقياس مقدار الجودة الكلي،
The measure of fit.
وقياس مدى ملاءمتها.
Which was the data likelihood, the thing that's bigger is better,
والذي كان عبارة عن احتمالية البيانات، الأشياء التي تكون أكبر تكون أفضل،
how well I fit the data, and then the magnitude of the coefficients,
كيف يمكنني ملاءمة البيانات، وبعد ذلك حجم المعاملات،
where the coefficients are too big are problematic.
عندما تكون المعاملات كبيرة جدا فذلك يسبب معضلة،
So we have one thing that we want to be big, the likelihood, and
ولذا، لدينا شيء والذي نريده أن يكون ضخم، ألا وهو الاحتمالية،
the other thing we want to be small, which is the minds of coefficients,
وشيء آخر والذي نريده أن يكون صغيرًا، ألا وهو المعاملات،
we're going to optimize the quality minus this complex metric here.
وسنقوم باستمثال الجودة - هذا المقياس المعقد هنا،
And so we want to balance between the two.
ولذا، فإننا نود الموازنة بين كلٍ منهما.
So what do those mean?
ولذا، ماذا يعني ذلك؟
Let's substantiate that more clearly In the context of logistic regression.
ودعونا نُثبت ذلك، بشكل أكثر وضوحًا، في سياق الانحدار اللوجستي،
The quality metric in logistic regression is the data likelihood, and
مقياس الجودة في الانحدار اللوجستي هو عبارة عن احتمالية البيانات،
we talked about it quite a bit in the previous module.
وقد تحدثنا عنه بقدر قليل في الوحدة السابقة.
Now one little side note here that we're going to use in this module
والآن، فإن الملاحظة الجانبية البسيطة والتي سنستخدمها في هذه الوحدة،
is that we don't typically optimize the data likelihood directly.
هي أننا لا نقوم باستمثال احتمالية البيانات إجماليًا بشكل مباشر،
We optimize the log of the data likelihood,
ولكننا نقوم باستمثال اللوغاريتم في احتمالية البيانات.
because that makes math a lot simpler.
حيث إن ذلك يجعل العملية الحسابية أكثر بساطة،
And it makes the gradients behave a lot better.
ويجعل التدرجات تتصرف على نحو أفضل.
In the options section in the previous model,
وقد تحدثنا عن الجودة فسم الاختيارات في الوحدة السابقة،
we talked about this quite a bit, and we explored it in detail.
وقد تحدثنا عن ذلك بقدر قليل، ولكننا استعرضناه بالتفصيل،
If you skipped that section,
وإذا قمت بتخطي هذا القسم،
just think about the log as a way to make those numbers less extreme.
فيجب أن تفكر في اللوغاريتم كطريقة لجعل تلك الأرقام أقل إفراطًا،
So we take the log.
ولذا، فإننا نأخذ اللوغاريتم،
So the method for quality is going to be the log of the data likelihood,
ولهذا، فإن مقياس الجودة سيكون اللوغاريتم بالنسبة لاحتمالية البيانات،
and we're going to make that log as big as possible.
وسنقوم بجعل هذا اللوغاريتم أكبر ما يمكننا،
So we see that the likelihood is going to be what we're going to optimize when
ولذا، فإننا نلاحظ أن الاحتمالية هي ما سنقوم باستمثاله،
we try to make it big.
عندما نحاول أن نجعلها أكبر،
But at the same time, we're trying to make something small,
ولكن في نفس الوقت، سنقوم بالمحاولة أن نجعلها شيء ما أصغر حجمًا،
which is the magnitude of the coefficient.
والذي هو حجم المعامل.
So there are different metrics for
ولذا، يوجد العديد من المقاييس
magnitude of coefficients, just like we explored in regression.
لحجم المعاملات، كما استعرضنا ذلك في الانحدار،
There's two that we're going to use in this module.
ويوجد منها اثنتان سنقوم باستخدامهما في هذه الوحدة،
One is the sum of the squares, also called the L2 norm, the square of the L2 norm.
الأولى، وهي مجموع التربيعات وتسمى (L2 NORM)، تربيعات L2 NORM.
And because it's noted by W2 squared and it's just very simple.
ولأن ذلك لوحظ من خلال W2 تربيع، ولذا فهو بسيط جدًا.
It's the square of the first coefficient plus the square
وهو تربيع المعامل الأول + التربيع للمعامل الثاني
of the second coefficient plus the square of the third coefficient and so
+ التربيع للمعامل الثالث، وهكذا.
on plus the square of the last coefficient, w d squared.
+ تربيع المعامل الأخير، تربيع WD.
That's if you used the L2 norm.
وهذا، في حال استخدمت L2 NORM.
We can also use the sum of the absolute values, also called the L1 norm,
ويمكننا أيضًا مجموع القيم المطلقة، والتي نُسميها أيضًا L1 NORM.
and it's denoted by this here.
ويمكن الاستدلال على ذلك من هنا.
And instead of being the squares, it's w0, absolute value,
وبدلاً من أن تكون عبارة عن التربيعات، فإنها تكون W0، القيمة المطلقة،
plus W one absolute value plus w two
+ W1 قيمة مطلقة + W2 قيمة مطلقة
absolute value all the way to the absolute value of the last coefficient.
وكذلك الحال مع القيمة المطلقة للمعامل الأخير.
Now in the regression course we explored these notions quite a bit but
وقد قمنا باستعراض تلك الأفكار بقدر قليل من التفصيل،
the main reason we take the square of the absolute value is that we want to
ولكن السبب الرئيسي الكامن وراء اختيارنا لتربيع القيم المطلقة
make sure to penalize highly positive and highly negative numbers in the same way,
هو أننا نريد التخلص من الأعداد ذات الإيجابية المرتفعة وكذلك الأرقام ذات السلبية المرتفعة بنفس الطريقة،
so by doing the search squaring of some value, i'll make the output here positive.
ولذا ومن خلال القيام بالتربيع على القيمة المطلقة، فإنني سأجعل القيمة هنا إيجابية.
When I make this norms as low as possible.
عندما أقوم بجعل تلك المعايير منخفضة قدر الإمكان.
So both of these approaches are penalize larger weight.
ولذا فإن كلاً من الطريقتين تقوم بالتخلص من الحجم الأكبر.
Actually, i should say penalize large coefficients.
وفي الحقيقة، يجب أن أقول، هي عبارة عن التخلص من المعاملات الكبيرة.
However, as we saw in the regression class by using the L one norm,
ومع ذلك، وكما رأينا في فئة الانحدار، فإنني يمكن أحصل على ما يسمى حلول متفرقة
I'm also going to get what's called a sparse solution.
من خلال استخدام L1 NORM.
So the sparse doesn't point play in regression but
ولذا فإن الحلول المتفرقة ليست جوهرية في الانحدار،
it also plays a role in classification for example.
ولكنها تلعب دورًا هامًا في التصنيف على سبيل المثال.
And in this module we're going to explore a little bit of both of these concepts.
وفي هذه الوحدة، سنقوم باستعراض كلا المفهومين بقدر قليل.
And we're going to start with the L2 norm, or the sum of the squares.
وسنقوم بالبدء مع L2 NORM أو مجموع التربيعات،
So now that we've reviewed these concepts, we can now formalize the problem,
وبما أننا قد قمنا بمراجعة تلك المفاهيم، يمكننا تشكيل المشكلة،
the quality that we're trying to maximize.
والجودة التي نريد زيادتها،
And so I want to maximize
ولذا، فأنا أريد بزيادتها
over my choice parameter W's of the trade off between two things.
من خلال معلمة الاختيار W للمفاضلة بين شيئين،
The likelihood of my data and actually the log of it.
وهما احتمالية البيانات الخاصة بي واللوغاريتم الفعلي لها.
So, log of the data likelihood.
ولذا، فاحتمالية البيانات للوغاريتم،
And some notion of penalty for the magnitude of the coefficients,
وجزء من فكرة التخلص من أحجام المعاملات،
which it will start with this L2 penalty notion.
والتي تتجلى من خلال فكرة التخلص L2 تلك.
[MUSIC]
[موسيقى]